Register of the Tadeusz Podgórski papers, 1952-1986
Hoover Institution Archives
Tadeusz Podgórski papers
1952-1986
2014C16
Hoover Institution Archives
12 manuscript boxes (4.8 linear feet)
Podgórski, Tadeusz.
Access
The collection is open for research. The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2014.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biograpgical Note
Tadeusz Podgórski was born November 15, 1919, in Zakroczym, Poland. He spent his youth in the working class Wola district of Warsaw. In 1939 he graduated from the Warszawskie Liceum Techniczno-Kolejowe and, in 1942, enlisted with the Armia Krajowa (Polish Home Army). During the war years he finished Officer Cadet training in the rank of Second Lieutenant.
From 1942 until 1944, Podgórski studied economics and sociology in the underground Warsaw University. During the Warsaw Uprising, he fought in the group “Radoslaw” and was wounded on two occasions. During that time, he was also captured and interned in the Stalag X-B prisoner-of-war camp in Sandbostel, Germany. Podgórski was active in his journalist career from very early on. During his military career he wrote for the military weekly Taran and underground magazines such as Zryw and Kadra. He immigrated to England in 1946 where he became involved in Polish émigré affairs.
Podgórski is perhaps best known for his heavy involvement with the Polska Partia Socjalistyczna (PPS - Polish Socialist Party) and his close friendship with Adam Ciolkosz (publicist, politician, and an important leader of the Polish Socialist Party). His involvement with the PPS was both as a member and a chairman. In 1965 he moved to Munich where he became the Chairman of the main PPS committee in Germany. While in this role he represented PPS in the Émigré Parliament – National Council of Poland (Rada Narodowa RP) both in England and Germany. Beginning in 1965, and for 20 consecutive years, he was editor of the section on Polish labor issues of Radio Free Europe in Munich. His broadcasts were positively received, gaining him wide popularity.
Tadeusz Podgórski was one of the most influential political activists for Polish émigré affairs of his time. A lifelong advocate of Democratic Socialism, he is credited with bringing into the ranks of PPS various activists from the Solidarnosc (Solidarity) party. He retired in London in 1985 and died there on August 5th, 1986. His final resting place is the Putney Vale cemetery next to his mentor and friend Adam Ciolkosz.
Scope and Contents
The collection documents the activities of Tadeusz Podgórski in his role as a journalist, political activist, a member of the PPS (Polska Partia Socjalistyczna) and editor of the section on Polish labor issues of Radio Free Europe-Munich. The collection is largely composed of correspondence, photographs, polish émigré affairs documents, PPS administrative documents and publications, Radio Free Europe documents, and writings by Podgórski and some of his colleagues.
Polska Partia Socjalistyczna.; Poland--Emigration and immigration.; Socialism--Poland.
- Correspondence, 1952-1986
  Scope and Contents
  Composed of various letters sent and received by Podgórski, postcards, greeting cards, and telegrams. The correspondence is both personal and professional in nature and is divided into four subtopics: émigré affairs, personal, Polska Partia Socjalistyczna, and Radio Free Europe.
  - Addresses, 1952-1986 (Text 1: 1)
  - Emigre Affairs, 1952-1986
    Correspondence between Podgórski and individuals who departed Poland after the implementation of martial law and were seeking asylum, particularly in Germany. Many of the letters were sent from refugee camps in which the émigrés were residing after leaving Poland.
    - Adamczyk, Marian, 1982 (Text 1: 2)
    - Baluka, Edmund, 1973-1974 (Text 1: 3)
    - Bialostocki, Witold, 1981 (Text 1: 4)
    - Bielachowicz, Aleksandra i Ryszard, 1983 (Text 1: 5)
    - Bielawski, Krzysztof, 1982 (Text 1: 6)
    - Bogusiewicz, Waldemar, 1983 (Text 1: 7)
    - Borówka, Zbigniew, 1981 (Text 1: 8)
    - Boryczko, Jerzy, 1973, 1975 (Text 1: 9)
    - Cichonski, Pawel, 1984 (Text 1: 10)
    - Czulkowski, Antoni, 1972-1974 (Text 1: 11)
    - Dakowicz, Janusz, 1983 (Text 1: 12)
    - Dolbniak, Stanislaw, 1977 (Text 1: 13)
    - Donat-Olszweska, 1972 (Text 1: 14)
    - Drewniak, Krystyna, 1983 (Text 1: 15)
    - Duda, Zdzislaw, 1983-1984 (Text 1: 16)
    - Dulisch, Waldemar, 1973, 1981 (Text 1: 17)
    - Fall, Jacek, 1981 (Text 1: 18)
    - Filipów, Jan, 1983 (Text 1: 19)
    - Frackiewicz, Wojciech, 1983 (Text 1: 20)
    - Gajda, Jerzy, 1982 (Text 1: 21)
    - Gajewski, Antoni, 1981 (Text 1: 22)
    - Glanowski, Antoni, 1968, 1973 (Text 1: 23)
    - Glowacki, Zbigniew, 1977 (Text 1: 24)
    - Grodzki, Wincenty, 1983-1984 (Text 1: 25)
    - Haber, Lukasz, 1982 (Text 1: 26)
    - Idzinski, Marcin, 1985 (Text 1: 27)
    - Jakubowski, Jan, 1976, 1982 (Text 1: 28)
    - Kicala, Lech, 1982 (Text 1: 29)
    - Komorowski, Z., 1983 (Text 1: 30)
    - Korman, Henryk, 1981 (Text 1: 31)
    - Koziel, Andrzej, 1982 (Text 1: 32)
    - Kruk, Artur i Aurelia, 1985 (Text 1: 33)
    - Kumanski, Zofia i Wlodzimierz, 1984 (Text 1: 34)
    - Lewandowski, Stanislaw, 1981 (Text 1: 35)
    - Lipinski, Wlodzimierz, 1985 (Text 1: 36)
    - Lukaszyk, Franciszek, 1982 (Text 1: 37)
    - Mohr, Zdzislaw, 1974 (Text 1: 38)
    - Motyl, Zdzislaw, 1981 (Text 1: 39)
    - Odrobny, Kazimierz, 1977 (Text 1: 40)
    - Pagenkopf, Jutta, 1977 (Text 1: 41)
    - Panczyk, Zdzislaw, 1983 (Text 1: 42)
    - Paradowski, Artur, 1977 (Text 1: 43)
    - Pawelski, Wieslaw, 1975 (Text 1: 44)
    - Pietraszewski, Eugeniusz, 1985 (Text 1: 45)
    - Piórkowski, Roman, 1982 (Text 1: 46)
    - Pisarek, Edward, 1986 (Text 1: 47)
    - Przebindowski, E., 1981 (Text 1: 48)
    - Pysz, J., 1979 (Text 1: 49)
    - Rogowin, Stefan, 1983 (Text 1: 50)
    - Rudnicki, Ryszard, 1984 (Text 1: 51)
    - Serdiukow, Iwona, 1977 (Text 1: 52)
    - Sieradz, Jerzy, 1981 (Text 1: 53)
    - Sierotwinska, Maria, 1982 (Text 1: 54)
    - Sima, Jerzy, 1983 (Text 1: 55)
    - Slonecki, Ferdynand, 1982 (Text 1: 56)
    - Srokowski, Leszek, 1981-1982 (Text 1: 57)
    - Stefanowicz, Malgorzata, 1981 (Text 1: 58)
    - Stempinski, Stefan, 1982 (Text 1: 59)
    - Szkopiak, Zygmunt, 1986 (Text 1: 60)
    - Whittaker, G. E., 1977 (Text 1: 61)
    - Wiszniewski, Piotr, 1973, 1977 (Text 1: 62)
    - Wójcicki, Tadeusz, 1984 (Text 1: 63)
    - Wybacz, L., 1983 (Text 1: 64)
    - Zajac, Bogdan, 1982 (Text 1: 65)
    - Zbyszewski, Karol, 1974, 1982 (Text 1: 66)
    - Zielinski, Marcin, 1982 (Text 1: 67)
    - Zwarycz, Andrzej, 1982 (Text 1: 68)
    - Zwierzynska, Zofia, 1982 (Text 1: 69)
    - Unidentified, 1972-1986 (Text 1: 70)
  - Personal file, 1952-1986
    Correspondence of a personal nature between Podgórski and his family and friends. Included in the personal correspondence are postcards and greeting cards.
    - Bartakowie, Anna i Przemyslaw, 1979 (Text 1: 71)
    - Blank Postcards, circa 1980 (Text 1: 72)
    - Cosewska, Mariola, 1974 (Text 1: 73)
    - Emilia, 1974 (Text 1: 74)
    - Gliwa, Maria, 1986 (Text 1: 75)
    - Grudkowski, Edmund, 1981 (Text 1: 76)
    - Hoffmeister, Reinhart, circa 1980 (Text 1: 77)
    - Hunt, J. A., 1982 (Text 1: 78)
    - Kliszewski, Barbara, 1984 (Text 1: 79)
    - Kon, Sever, 1975-1976 (Text 1: 80)
    - Kowalczewski, A. A., 1966-1974 (Text 1: 81)
    - Kuba (Quba,), 1972-1985 (Text 1: 82)
    - Linowiecki, Walenty, 1986 (Text 1: 83)
    - Nawolski, Marian, 1982 (Text 1: 84)
    - Petlicki, Jerzy, 1984-1985 (Text 1: 85)
    - Podgórski, Klara, 1986 (Text 1: 86)
    - Podgórski, Nina, 1986 (Text 1: 87)
    - Pohlenz, Arnolt, 1982 (Text 1: 88)
    - Polozynski, Antoni, 1969-1974 (Text 1: 89)
    - Proszowski, Piotr, 1985-1986 (Text 1: 90)
    - Przyluski, Bronislaw, 1974 (Text 1: 91)
    - Reis, Matthias, 1986 (Text 1: 92)
    - Sawicka, Teresa, 1985 (Text 1: 93)
    - Sroga, Czeslaw i Zena, 1974 (Text 1: 94)
    - Stefanowski, Roman, 1974-1975 (Text 1: 95)
    - Szulczewski, Cezary, 1977 (Text 1: 96)
    - Swierczak, Janusz, 1982 (Text 1: 97)
    - Werth, Reinhold, 1985 (Text 1: 98)
    - Wojciechowski, Thomas, 1981 (Text 2: 1)
    - Zabludowski, Boleslaw, 1966 (Text 2: 2)
    - Zadrozny, Stanislaw, 1973 (Text 2: 3)
    - Zajaczkowski, Maciej, 1982 (Text 2: 4)
    - Unidentified, 1952-1986 (Text 2: 5)
  - Polska Partia Socjalistyczna file, 1965-1986
    Correspondence of a professional nature between Podgórski and various members of the PPS discussing political and administrative issues. Some of the correspondence includes letters from various individuals requesting PPS publications and/or information on joining the PPS.
    - Adamski, Pawel, 1983 (Text 2: 6)
    - Albertowicz, Wojciech, 1985 (Text 2: 7)
    - Arciszewski, Jan, 1982 (Text 2: 8)
    - Arlamowski, Jerzy, 1985 (Text 2: 9)
    - Astachnowicz, Boleslaw, 1982 (Text 2: 10)
    - Augustowski, Jacek, 1984-1986 (Text 2: 11)
    - Bajkowski, Stanislaw, 1986 (Text 2: 12)
    - Baranski, Ireneusz, 1977 (Text 2: 13)
    - Bak, Jan, 1983, 1986 (Text 2: 14)
    - Bak, Kazimierz, 1982-1983 (Text 2: 15)
    - Bek, Jan, 1986 (Text 2: 16)
    - Bialoboki, Witold, 1981-1982 (Text 2: 17)
    - Bielachowicz, Ryszard, 1986 (Text 2: 18)
    - Biello, Robert, 1985 (Text 2: 19)
    - Biezunski, Jerzy, 1983 (Text 2: 20)
    - Bilinski, J. M., 1984-1985 (Text 2: 21)
    - Blachnicki, Franciszek, 1984-1985 (Text 2: 22)
    - Blank Postcards, 1982 (Text 2: 23)
    - Blumsztajn, Seweryn, 1982 (Text 2: 24)
    - Bluta, Iwona, 1982 (Text 2: 25)
    - Blazynski, Zbigniew, 1983-1984 (Text 2: 26)
    - Bogacz, Ryszard, 1984-1986 (Text 2: 27)
    - Bohusz-Szyszko, Zygmunt, 1977 (Text 2: 28)
    - Borczyk, Stanislaw, 1972-1985 (Text 2: 29)
    - Borowska, Maria, 1984-1985 (Text 2: 30)
    - Borylo, Leszek, 1981 (Text 2: 31)
    - Broniwój-Orlinski, Wincenty, 1978-1982 (Text 2: 32)
    - Brzezinscy, Danuta i Piotr, 1984 (Text 2: 33)
    - Buczacki, Andrzej, 1980-1984 (Text 2: 34)
    - Bujak, Adam, 1980-1986 (Text 2: 35)
    - Buszewski, Ignacy, 1964-1982 (Text 2: 36)
    - Chelstowski, Wlodzimierz, 1984 (Text 2: 37)
    - Chilecki, Andrzej, 1975-1986 (Text 2: 38)
    - Chmielewski, Andrzej, 1971 (Text 2: 39)
    - Chodakowska, Krystyna, 1977 (Text 2: 40)
    - Chodakowski, Adam, 1977 (Text 2: 41)
    - Chodakowski, Jan, 1984-1986 (Text 2: 42)
    - Chodyna, Jacek, 1984, 1986 (Text 2: 43)
    - Chojecki, Miroslaw, 1982-1986 (Text 2: 44)
    - Chorazyna, H., 1982 (Text 2: 45)
    - Chyzynska, Hanna, 1981 (Text 2: 46)
    - Cichy, Gerard, 1986 (Text 2: 47)
    - Cienkusz, Feliks, 1986 (Text 2: 48)
    - Ciolkosz, Adam, 1952-1978 (Text 2: 49)
    - Ciolkosz, Lidia, 1965-1986 (Text 2: 50)
    - Ciszak, Alicja, 1983 (Text 2: 51)
    - Craxi, Betino, 1985 (Text 2: 52)
    - Cuper, Andrzej, 1982 (Text 2: 53)
    - Cybulski, K., 1979 (Text 2: 54)
    - Czarnecka, Florentyna, 1982 (Text 2: 55)
    - Czarnecki, Marian, 1973-1974 (Text 2: 56)
    - Czarnocka, Halina, 1985 (Text 2: 57)
    - Czerniawski, Roman, 1983 (Text 2: 58)
    - Czerwinski, Witold, 1973, 1982 (Text 2: 59)
    - Dabrowski, Henryk, 1974, 1981 (Text 2: 60)
    - Dehnel, Wladyslaw, 1971 (Text 2: 61)
    - Dlubak, Grzegorz, 1981 (Text 2: 62)
    - Domoradzki, Jerzy, 1977 (Text 2: 63)
    - Drozdek, Wojciech, 1983 (Text 2: 64)
    - Drzewinski, Franciszek, 1986 (Text 2: 65)
    - Duda, Zdzislaw, 1983 (Text 2: 66)
    - Durkalec, Jan, 1974-1984 (Text 2: 67)
    - Dykas, Stanislaw, 1981-1986 (Text 2: 68)
    - Dziamalek, Leon, 1977 (Text 2: 69)
    - Dziechciowski, Tadeusz, 1983-1984 (Text 2: 70)
    - Dziedzic-Erbmann, Rudolf, 1977 (Text 2: 71)
    - Dziewulak, Waclaw, 1978 (Text 2: 72)
    - Ehrenkreutz, Andrzej S., 1982 (Text 3: 1)
    - Felchnerowski, Tytus, 1982-1983 (Text 3: 2)
    - Filipowicz, T., 1983 (Text 3: 3)
    - Foks, Roman, 1986 (Text 3: 4)
    - Folek, Tadeusz, 1979-1985 (Text 3: 5)
    - Frendl, Ludwik, 1975-1985 (Text 3: 6)
    - Freudenheim, Mieczyslaw, 1977-1982 (Text 3: 7)
    - Gadzina, Piotr, 1984-1986 (Text 3: 8)
    - Galinski, Jerzy, 1986 (Text 3: 9)
    - Gajda, A., 1972, 1982 (Text 3: 10)
    - Gajewski, Antoni, 1981 (Text 3: 11)
    - Garztecki, Juliusz, 1984 (Text 3: 12)
    - Gawlik, Waclaw, 1982 (Text 3: 13)
    - Gella, Aleksander, 1974 (Text 3: 14)
    - Gidorowicz, Wlodzimierz, 1981 (Text 3: 15)
    - Giedroyc, Jerzy, 1977-1986 (Text 3: 16)
    - Gierlicki, Bogdan, 1984-1985 (Text 3: 17)
    - Gizowski, Ryszard, 1983 (Text 3: 18)
    - Glanowski, Antoni, 1975 (Text 3: 19)
    - Glowinski, Stefan, 1974-1975 (Text 3: 20)
    - Golik, M., 1975 (Text 3: 21)
    - Gonzalez, Felipe, 1982 (Text 3: 22)
    - Gorczynska, Barbara, 1986 (Text 3: 23)
    - Gosciniak, Slawomir, 1974 (Text 3: 24)
    - Gotowicz, Stanislaw, 1977 (Text 3: 25)
    - Górka, Stanislaw, 1965 (Text 3: 26)
    - Grabosz, Jan, 1977 (Text 3: 27)
    - Gross, Zygmunt, 1972-1975 (Text 3: 28)
    - Gruda, Konrad, 1977 (Text 3: 29)
    - Gruszka, Kazimierz, 1977, 1982 (Text 3: 30)
    - Gruszecki, Mieczyslaw, 1981-1982 (Text 3: 31)
    - Gruszecki, Wojciech, 1982-1985 (Text 3: 32)
    - Grzebula, Józef, 1984 (Text 3: 33)
    - Grzejszczyk, Grzegorz, 1983-1984 (Text 3: 34)
    - Grzemski, Józef, 1974 (Text 3: 35)
    - Grzesik, Ryszard, 1973 (Text 3: 36)
    - Gutowski, Antoni, 1974 (Text 3: 37)
    - Haber, Edmund, 1976-1977 (Text 3: 38)
    - Haber, Lukasz, 1982 (Text 3: 39)
    - von Halem, F., 1984-1985 (Text 3: 40)
    - Hanff, Konstanty, 1979 (Text 3: 41)
    - Hazubski, Jerzy, 1981 (Text 3: 42)
    - Healy, Denis, 1982 (Text 3: 43)
    - Heinsdorf, Helena, 1972 (Text 3: 44)
    - Hering, Alfons, 1983 (Text 3: 45)
    - Herling-Grudzinski, Gustaw, 1972 (Text 3: 46)
    - Hetzig, Zdzislaw, 1981 (Text 3: 47)
    - Heydenkern, Benedykt, 1972 (Text 3: 48)
    - Hulsz, Edmund, 1977-1982 (Text 3: 49)
    - Iranek-Osmecki, Kazimierz, 1976 (Text 3: 50)
    - Iwanow, Zbigniew, 1984, 1986 (Text 3: 51)
    - Jachowicz, Andrzej, 1974 (Text 3: 52)
    - Jagielski, Henryk, 1982 (Text 3: 53)
    - Jajszczyk, Jerzy, 1971-1972 (Text 3: 54)
    - Jakubowski, J., 1977, 1982 (Text 3: 55)
    - Jalowiecki, Stanislaw, 1984, 1986 (Text 3: 56)
    - Jamka, Lech, 1985 (Text 3: 57)
    - Jankowski, Jerzy, 1974-1986 (Text 3: 58)
    - Jareccy, Anna i Andrzej, 1985 (Text 3: 59)
    - Jasinski, Stanislaw, 1977, 1984 (Text 3: 60)
    - Jerzykowski, Henryk, 1978-1984 (Text 3: 61)
    - Kaczmarczyk, Józef, 1985 (Text 3: 62)
    - Kaczmarek, Stefan, 1974 (Text 3: 63)
    - Kaczmarek-Meller, A., 1974 (Text 3: 64)
    - Kaczorowski, Z., 1981 (Text 3: 65)
    - Kajkowski, Aleksander, 1982-1983 (Text 3: 66)
    - Kalapita, 1975 (Text 3: 67)
    - Kalinowski, Aleksander, 1982 (Text 3: 68)
    - Kaluzny, Romuald, 1982-1984 (Text 3: 69)
    - Kamienski, Ludwik, 1982-1984 (Text 3: 70)
    - Kaminski, Andrzej, 1977-1978 (Text 3: 71)
    - Kaminski, Grzegorz, 1985 (Text 3: 72)
    - Kaminski, Wiktor, 1982 (Text 3: 73)
    - Karonski, Mieczyslaw, 1981 (Text 3: 74)
    - Karpinski, Teodor, 1982 (Text 3: 75)
    - Kartzewski, Erwin, 1977, 1985 (Text 3: 76)
    - Kempf-Sokorski, Stanislaw, 1974 (Text 3: 77)
    - Kiciak, Antoni E., 1977 (Text 3: 78)
    - Kielbas, Sylwester, 1977 (Text 3: 79)
    - Kijak, Ryszard, 1982 (Text 3: 80)
    - Kindlein, Lucjan, 1981 (Text 3: 81)
    - Kisiel, Jacek, 1982 (Text 3: 82)
    - Klimczak, Edward, 1984-1985 (Text 3: 83)
    - Knap, Kazimierz, 1975 (Text 3: 84)
    - Kocala, Lech, 1982 (Text 3: 85)
    - Koczorowski, Grzegorz, 1984 (Text 3: 86)
    - Kolcz, Ludwig, 1982 (Text 3: 87)
    - Kolodziej, Andrzej, 1984-1985 (Text 3: 88)
    - Kon, Hilary Boguslaw, 1986 (Text 3: 89)
    - Koniarek, Krystyna, 1985 (Text 3: 90)
    - Kopec, Tomasz, 1983 (Text 3: 91)
    - Kopera, Lucjan, 1977 (Text 3: 92)
    - Korsak, Andrzej, 1984-1986 (Text 3: 93)
    - Koruszowicz, Maks, 1982 (Text 4: 1)
    - Kosmahl, Ireneusz, 1984 (Text 4: 2)
    - Koscinski, Andrzej, 1982 (Text 4: 3)
    - Kowal, Grzegorz, 1985 (Text 4: 4)
    - Kowalczyk, Andrzej, 1983 (Text 4: 5)
    - Kowalczyk, Janina i Zygmunt, 1980 (Text 4: 6)
    - Kowalski, Artur, 1976-1977 (Text 4: 7)
    - Kowalski, Jacek, 1977-1986 (Text 4: 8)
    - Kozlowski, Marek, 1982 (Text 4: 9)
    - Kozub-Piski, Zbigniew, 1984 (Text 4: 10)
    - Kozuchowski, Wladyslaw, 1986 (Text 4: 11)
    - Krawczyk, Zygmunt, 1983 (Text 4: 12)
    - Krawczynski, Teodor, 1977 (Text 4: 13)
    - Kroczak, Adam, 1982 (Text 4: 14)
    - Kronawitter, George, 1984 (Text 4: 15)
    - Krupinski, Jacek, 1982 (Text 4: 16)
    - Kryk, Andrzej, 1984-1985 (Text 4: 17)
    - Krzeminski, Józef, 1982 (Text 4: 18)
    - Kubala, Leszek, 1981-1983 (Text 4: 19)
    - Kucien, Zygmunt, 1984 (Text 4: 20)
    - Kudlicki, Stanislaw, 1973-1978 (Text 4: 21)
    - Kulakowski, Jan, 1981 (Text 4: 22)
    - Lasko, Tadeusz, 1982 (Text 4: 23)
    - Latkowski, Wieslaw, 1982 (Text 4: 24)
    - Ledwon, Waclaw, 1977 (Text 4: 25)
    - Lehnert, Marek, 1984 (Text 4: 26)
    - Lerski, Jerzy, 1982-1986 (Text 4: 27)
    - Len, Tadeusz, 1981-1984 (Text 4: 28)
    - Lewicki, Borys, 1984 (Text 4: 29)
    - Libig, Robert, circa 1980 (Text 4: 30)
    - Ligaszewski, Jacek, 1977 (Text 4: 31)
    - Lipczynski, Krzysztof, 1984-1985 (Text 4: 32)
    - Lisinski, Michal, 1974 (Text 4: 33)
    - Litonska, Irena, 1985 (Text 4: 34)
    - Lizak, Grzegorz, 1986 (Text 4: 35)
    - Lorczyk, Stanislaw, 1982 (Text 4: 36)
    - Lubinski, Waclaw, 1984 (Text 4: 37)
    - Lubowiecki, Edward, 1974 (Text 4: 38)
    - Luciejewski, Wojciech, 1982 (Text 4: 39)
    - Ludzuawska, Lidia, 1985 (Text 4: 40)
    - Latka, Janusz, 1984-1985 (Text 4: 41)
    - Lopacki, Czeslaw, 1975 (Text 4: 42)
    - Lubienski, Ludwik, 1977-1984 (Text 4: 43)
    - Lukomski, Kazimierz, 1976 (Text 4: 44)
    - Machtyl, Henryk, 1981-1985 (Text 4: 45)
    - Maciejczyk, Edward, 1984 (Text 4: 46)
    - Mack, Manfred, 1986 (Text 4: 47)
    - Mackiewicz, Stanislaw, 1982-1984 (Text 4: 48)
    - Madeyski, Maciej, 1984 (Text 4: 49)
    - Magiera, Mieczyslaw, 1982-1983 (Text 4: 50)
    - Mahler, R., 1981 (Text 4: 51)
    - Majchrzyk, Eugeniusz, 1984-1986 (Text 4: 52)
    - Majewska, Halina, 1982 (Text 4: 53)
    - Makulska, Grazyna, 1983 (Text 4: 54)
    - Malinowski, Boguslaw, 1986 (Text 4: 55)
    - Malolepszy, B., 1975 (Text 4: 56)
    - Mantel, Feliks, 1972-1984 (Text 4: 57)
    - Marciniak, Wiktor, 1979 (Text 4: 58)
    - Marek, Krystyna, 1982-1983 (Text 4: 59)
    - Markowski, Alexander, 1972-1977 (Text 4: 60)
    - Marks, Boleslaw, 1986 (Text 4: 61)
    - Matusiak, Slawomir, 1985 (Text 4: 62)
    - Matuszewski, Miroslaw, 1977-1982 (Text 4: 63)
    - Matwiejczyk, Edward, 1984 (Text 4: 64)
    - Mazur, Stefan, 1975 (Text 4: 65)
    - Merlo, B., 1974 (Text 4: 66)
    - Mianowicz, Tomasz, 1982 (Text 4: 67)
    - Michalik, Henryk, 1977 (Text 4: 68)
    - Michalikowski, Jerzy, 1977 (Text 4: 69)
    - Michno, Stefan, 1972-1974 (Text 4: 70)
    - Mieczkowski, Jan, 1977 (Text 4: 71)
    - Mikiciuk, Stanislaw, 1979-1985 (Text 4: 72)
    - Mikolajczuk, Marek, 1982 (Text 4: 73)
    - Mirowski, Marian, 1974-1983 (Text 4: 74)
    - Modrzejewska, Jadwiga, 1986 (Text 4: 75)
    - Molinski, Bogdan, 1982 (Text 4: 76)
    - Morgiewicz, Emil, 1984 (Text 4: 77)
    - Morkowski, Jan, 1974 (Text 4: 78)
    - Mroczkowski, Jerzy, 1974-1986 (Text 4: 79)
    - Mrzyglód, Janusz, 1982-1985 (Text 4: 80)
    - Muller, Adolf, 1982 (Text 4: 81)
    - Muszynski, Z. H., 1975 (Text 4: 82)
    - Mutkowski, Jan, 1975 (Text 4: 83)
    - Nabozny, Kazimierz, 1982-1984 (Text 4: 84)
    - Nedzynski, Stefan, 1974-1981 (Text 4: 85)
    - Niciecka, Halina, 1982-1985 (Text 4: 86)
    - Nietyksza, Anna Kasia, 1985 (Text 4: 87)
    - Nowak, Jan, 1968-1984 (Text 4: 88)
    - Nowakowski, Tadeusz, 1982, 1985 (Text 4: 89)
    - Nowotarski, Rose, 1977 (Text 4: 90)
    - Nowotny, Wiktor, 1977 (Text 4: 91)
    - Nurkowska, Krystyna, 1982-1985 (Text 4: 92)
    - Odojewski, Wlodzimierz, 1982-1985 (Text 4: 93)
    - Olejnik, Wlodzimierz, 1982-1986 (Text 4: 94)
    - Osadczuk, Bohdan, 1977 (Text 5: 1)
    - Ostrowski, Jan, 1974-1984 (Text 5: 2)
    - Palmer, Maria, 1986 (Text 5: 3)
    - Panczyk, Zdzislaw, 1983 (Text 5: 4)
    - Parczynski, Janusz, 1981 (Text 5: 5)
    - Paruszewski, Tomasz, 1982 (Text 5: 6)
    - Paterak, Wladyslaw, 1985 (Text 5: 7)
    - Pelc, Maksmilian, 1975 (Text 5: 8)
    - Perendyk, Klaudiusz, 1980 (Text 5: 9)
    - Pieczynski, Taduesz, 1981 (Text 5: 10)
    - Pieniazek, Andrzej, 1977 (Text 5: 11)
    - Pienko, Henryk, 1982-1983 (Text 5: 12)
    - Pietrzykowski, Jerzy, 1982 (Text 5: 13)
    - Pluta, Irena, 1982 (Text 5: 14)
    - Platek, Lidia, 1978 (Text 5: 15)
    - Pniewski, Zbigniew, 1982 (Text 5: 16)
    - Podgórski, Julian, 1974 (Text 5: 17)
    - Podrzycki, Bohdan, 1976-1984 (Text 5: 18)
    - Poleski, Jerzy, 1977 (Text 5: 19)
    - Pomian, Andrzej, 1979-1986 (Text 5: 20)
    - Pomian, Krzysztof, 1977 (Text 5: 21)
    - Pomiatowski, J., 1965 (Text 5: 22)
    - Pomorski, Waclaw, 1972 (Text 5: 23)
    - Pozerski, Olgierd, 1982-1986 (Text 5: 24)
    - Prasalski, Daniel, 1984 (Text 5: 25)
    - Prokopowicz, T., 1967-1971 (Text 5: 26)
    - Przybylak, Lucjan, 1974 (Text 5: 27)
    - Przyjemski, Janusz, 1980 (Text 5: 28)
    - Puacz, Edward, 1974 (Text 5: 29)
    - Racieski, Zbigniew, 1984 (Text 5: 30)
    - Raczynski, Edward, 1982-1986 (Text 5: 31)
    - Reiss-Czemplik, Ryszard, 1981-1985 (Text 5: 32)
    - Reminger-Nabozny, Kazimierz, 1985-1986 (Text 5: 33)
    - Rogowicz, Stefan, 1983-1985 (Text 5: 34)
    - Rolicz, Andrzej, 1984-1986 (Text 5: 35)
    - Rolke, Tadeusz, 1978 (Text 5: 36)
    - Rondomanska, Maryla, 1985 (Text 5: 37)
    - Rosembusch, Adam, 1986 (Text 5: 38)
    - Rosien, Adolf, 1982 (Text 5: 39)
    - Rosz, Nina, 1986 (Text 5: 40)
    - Roszkowska, M., 1982 (Text 5: 41)
    - Rothemund, Helmut, 1985 (Text 5: 42)
    - Rózankowska, Zofia, 1972-1984 (Text 5: 43)
    - Rózankowski, Kazimierz, 1977-1984 (Text 5: 44)
    - Rudzki, Adam, 1985 (Text 5: 45)
    - Rusin, Leszek, 1982-1986 (Text 5: 46)
    - Ryser-Szymanski, Witold, 1983-1985 (Text 5: 47)
    - Rysz, Jadwiga, 1977 (Text 5: 48)
    - Rzepecka, Aneta, 1985 (Text 5: 49)
    - Rzepka, Adolf, 1984 (Text 5: 50)
    - Sabbat, Kazimierz, 1974-1986 (Text 5: 51)
    - Sadlak, Zbigniew, 1986 (Text 5: 52)
    - Sadlowska, Helena S., 1977 (Text 5: 53)
    - Sadowski, Jeremi, 1977 (Text 5: 54)
    - Sak, Julian, 1974-1986 (Text 5: 55)
    - Salapatek, Dariusz, 1984 (Text 5: 56)
    - Samol, Wieslaw, 1982-1985 (Text 5: 57)
    - Saniecki, Leopold, 1965 (Text 5: 58)
    - Sas-Skowronski, M., 1977 (Text 5: 59)
    - Sawicki, Jerzy, 1985 (Text 5: 60)
    - Scholtz, Zbigniew, 1984 (Text 5: 61)
    - Schonhuber, Franz, 1978 (Text 5: 62)
    - Serget, B., 1965-1966 (Text 5: 63)
    - Sekowska, Jadwiga, 1977 (Text 5: 64)
    - Sielecki, Karol, 1981 (Text 5: 65)
    - Sikorski, J., 1981 (Text 5: 66)
    - Skibinska, Aleksandra, 1986 (Text 5: 67)
    - Skrzynski, Wlodzimierz, 1972-1975 (Text 5: 68)
    - Slawinski, Kazimierz, 1975-1986 (Text 5: 69)
    - Slomkowski, Wojciech, 1985 (Text 5: 70)
    - Slowakiewcz, Jan, 1977 (Text 5: 71)
    - Smolar, Eugeniusz, 1974-1978 (Text 5: 72)
    - Snastin, Aleksander, 1984 (Text 5: 73)